

Pauravee Sathe

Vocalist, Music Teacher

A passionate music enthusiast and dedicated professional musician, I embarked on my musical journey under the guidance of Mrs. Vinita Joshi, my first guru in Light Music, at the age of six. Driven by an insatiable quest for knowledge in music, I further honed my skills under the expert tutelage of Dr. Madhuri Dongre, a distinguished classical vocalist specializing in the Gwalior Gharana. I am privileged to have received more than 14 years of comprehensive training under her mentorship. My educational background includes an M.A. in Indian Classical Music, and I am a NET-qualified professional. Additionally, I have completed a music therapy course, utilizing the healing power of ragas to address specific ailments. I was recently awarded a B grade in a radio audition by Prasar Bharati, Akashwani Pune, which is a significant milestone in my career. Deeply committed to music education, I find joy in teaching both online and offline. Furthermore, I bring ample experience in college administration.

- pauraveesathe@gmail.com
- B-304, Platinum Park, Hinjewadi Phase 2, Pune 411057. India
- § pau_sathe

- 9028797281
- in linkedin.com/in/Pauravee Sathe
- instagram.com/sathepauravee

WORK EXPERIENCE

Assistant Professor & Academic Coordinator Maharashtra Education Society's College of Performing Arts, Pune.

01/2022 - 03/2023

Roles & Responsibilities

- Administrative exposure Managed student's section, providing guidance, counseling, and addressing grievances.
- Music faculty- Imparted comprehensive musical lessons covering both theory and practical aspects.
- Admission Cell Conducted career counseling and organized auditions. Planned and executed various events. Established and maintained connections with parents/guardians.
- Member of College Advisory Committee- Presented requirements for funds and resources to the advisory board. Successfully implemented approved initiatives for college administration.

Assistant Professor (Music-Vocal) MIT Art Design and Technology University, Pune

07/2018 - 11/2020 MIT Vishwashanti Sangeet Kala Academy Rajbaug, Loni Kalbhor, Pune

Pune

Roles & Responsibilities

- Music Faculty- Imparted comprehensive musical lessons, covering both theory and practical aspects. Conducted engaging lecture demonstrations for students. Scheduling and planning academic year activities for music students.
- Exam coordinator- Planned and coordinated internal and external exams. Managed continuous assessments, tutorials, and paper setting. Conducted evaluations and fulfilled invigilation duties.
- Member of Board of studies- Actively participated in syllabus designing for music courses. Contributed to the development of the evaluation matrix.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts (Music) SNDT Women's University, Mumbai.

06/2005 - 05/2008 SNDT Arts & Commerce College, Karve road, Pune.

Master of Arts (Music) SNDT Women's University, Mumbai.

06/2008 - 05/2010 SNDT Arts & Commerce College, Karve road, Pune.

Sangeet Visharad Bharatiya Prasarak Mandal, Pune.

06/2009 - 07/2010 Gandharva Mahavidyalaya, shanivar peth , Pune.

NET (National Eligibility Test)University Grants Commission (UGC)

06/2013 MUSIC

SKILLS

Core teaching ability- experience of teaching classical music to varied age groups & exposing them to various musical genres.

Technical Skills - 1. Google certified educator

Technical Skills - 2. Conversant with MS Office utilities (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)

Technical Skills - 3. Working knowledge of internet and web based applications (Skype, Zoom, Web ex, etc.)

Designing and planning of various events from an academic perspective.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Music Teacher Sanskriti School

01/2018 - 05/2018

Undri. Pune

Roles & Responsibilities

- Vocal Training: Instruct students in singing. Offer guidance on proper techniques, posture, and musical expression.
- Organizing Performances: Plan and organize musical events, concerts, or recitals to showcase students' talents. Coordinate logistics, rehearsals, and ensure a smooth execution of performances.
- Assessment and Feedback: Assess students' musical abilities and progress through regular evaluations. Provide constructive feedback to help students improve their skills and reach their potential.

Visiting Faculty

Department of Music, SNDT Post Graduation Studies & Research College

07/2014 - 08/2015

Karve road. Pune

Roles & Responsibilities

- Artistic Direction: Provide artistic direction for ensembles, orchestras, choirs, or other musical groups. Plan and conduct rehearsals to prepare students for performances.
- Professional Development: Engage in ongoing professional development to stay current with advancements in music education, pedagogy, and performance.

Research Executive (Music) Opentech Software Systems Pvt. Ltd.

12/2011 - 12/2013

Mayur Colony, Kothrud, Pune

Roles & Responsibilities

- Identification of Budding Artists- Recognized and nurtured emerging talent within the musical community.
- Musical Data Management- Efficiently managed musical data, ensuring accuracy and accessibility.
- Content Management- Oversaw content for the company's musicrelated webpage. Ensured the webpage's relevance and engagement with the audience.

SCHOLARSHIPS

Late Pt. Ramrao Koratkar Memorial Scholarship (01/2015) (01/2015)

Ganawardhan, Pune

 Received a scholarship in the memory of Late Pt. Ramrao Koratkar from Ganawardhan, Pune, in recognition of dedication to learning and performing Indian classical music.

Late Dattatray Dhondopant Ratnaparkhi Memorial Scholarship (01/2013) (01/2013)

Ganawardhan, Pune

 Received a scholarship in memory of Late Dattatray Dhondopant Ratnaparkhi from Ganawardhan, Pune, in recognition of dedication to learning and performing Indian classical music.

Late Usha Tai Mujumdar Memorial Scholarship (01/2012) (01/2012)

Ganawardhan, Pune

 Received a scholarship in memory of Late Usha Tai Mujumdar from Ganawardhan, Pune, in recognition of dedication to learning and performing Indian classical music.

CERTIFICATE COURSES

Google Certified Educator Course_Level 2 (11/2024)

proficiency in using Teaching apps, Digital Pedagogy & Modern Teaching Practices.

Certificate Course _Masterclass on Elevate Teaching and Learning with AI (05/2024)

Conducted by Up Educators -partner google for education.

Certificate Course _Masterclass on Gamification in Education: Making and Learning Fun & Effective (03/2024)

Certificate Course _Masterclass on English Integration with technology (03/2024)

Conducted by Up Educators -partner google for education.

Certificate Course_Masterclass on Chat GPT and AI tools for education (09/2023)

Conducted by Up Educators -partner google for education.

Certificate Course_Masterclass on Advanced Excel for education (09/2023)

Conducted by Up Educators -partner google for education.

Certificate Course_Masterclass on Creating Designs using Canva (08/2023)

Conducted by Up Educators -partner google for education.

Workshop_Adobe Express Training (03/2023)

Organized by SPPU and approved by AICTE-All India council for technical education

Workshop_Bootcamp FYUP on NEP 2023 (01/2023)

organized by Maharashtra Education Society, Pune

Google Certified Educator Course_Level 1 (05/2022)

proficiency in using Teaching apps, Digital Pedagogy & Modern Teaching Practices.

Japanese Language (N5 level) (04/2021 - 10/2021) Bhasha Institute, Institute of Foreign Languages, Pune

Techniques of Riyaz in Indian Music (12/2020)

National Workshop and Webinar on the mentioned subject was organized by Department of Music, Dev Samaj College of Women, Firozepur

Various Dimensions of Teaching Music-yesterday, today and tomorrow. (08/2020)

National Workshop and Webinar on the mentioned subject was organized by Department of Music, Ramgarhia Girls College, Ludhiana

Education 4.0: Teacher's Training (07/2020)

FDP on TCSiON Learning Management System by MITADT University, Pune

Virtual Classroom: A necessity in Performing Arts Education (05/2020)

National Webinar on mentioned subject was organized by department of Indian Classical Music-Vocal, Faculty of Performing Arts, The Maharaja Sayajirao University of Baroda on 26 th May 2020

Teacher Certificate Course for Hindustani Classical Vocal Music (09/2017 - 12/2017)

Shankar Mahadevan Academy, Bengaluru.

Music Therapy Certificate Course (07/2013 - 01/2014)

Sur Sanjeevan Music Therapy Trust, Mumbai.

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Grade B (Akashwani Graded Artist) (12/2024)

The grade is been awarded in a radio audition by Prasar Bharati, Akashwani Pune

Sangeet Sanmaan 2021 (03/2021)

An appreciation for the valuable participation and winning Dr. Ashok Da. Ranade classical vocal competition, A worldwide competition of Indian classical music, organized by 'Vertical Notes' in March 2021.

Best team leader award (12/2018)

An appreciation for the valuable participation in the Yuva Spandan, 34th edition of the West Zone Inter University Youth Festival hosted by Savitribai Phule Pune University, as a team leader of MIT ADT University.

University Topper (2008 & 2010)

An appreciation for excelling in Academics as well as bringing laurels to the SNDT University in the field of culture.

"Ganahira" Paritoshik Prize in Music (01/2011)

for securing the highest number of marks in Entire: Music at the Master of Arts Examination at the 60th Annual Convocation Ceremony.

Padmashree Kalyanji "Gold Medal" (01/2011)

for securing the highest number of marks in Entire: Music at the Master of Arts Examination at the 60th Annual Convocation Ceremony.

Shri. C. Ramchandra Music Prize (01/2011)

for securing the highest number of marks in Entire: Music at the Master of Arts Examination at the 60th Annual Convocation Ceremony.

Shri. Pandharinath Moroba Mungre Prize (01/2011)

for standing First at the Master of Arts Examination with Vocal Music in the whole University at the 60th Annual Convocation Ceremony.

Late Mrs. Prabha G. Mokashi (Godbole) Music Prize (01/2011)

for standing First at the Master of Arts Examination with Entire: Music at the 60th Annual Convocation Ceremony.

Ganapriya Sau. Kusumawati Vishnu Dabli Prize (01/2011)

for standing First at the Master of Arts Examination with Music at the 60th Annual Convocation Ceremony.

Usha Umarani Prize (01/2011)

for securing the highest number of marks in Entire: Music at the Master Of Arts Examination at the 60th Annual Convocation Ceremony.

Late Shri. Shiv M. Khare Prize (01/2011)

for Music for securing the highest number of marks in the Master Of Arts Examination with Music at the 60th Annual Convocation Ceremony.

Shri. Vasant Desai Music Prize (02/2009)

for securing the highest number of marks in D.C Music at the Bachelor of Arts Examination at the 58th Annual Convocation Ceremony.

Smt. Shamlabai Majgaonkar Prize (02/2009)

for Music for securing the highest number of marks in D.C Music at the Bachelor of Arts Examination at the 58th Annual Convocation Ceremony.

Shri. S. V. Joshi Prize (02/2009)

for standing First from amongst the candidates of the S.N.D.T. Arts & Commerce College for Women, Pune at the Bachelor of Arts Examination at the 58th Annual Convocation Ceremony.

Sau. Shardabai Atre (Gwalior) Prize (02/2009)

for securing the highest number of marks in the subject of D.C Music from amongst the candidates of B.A. /M.A. Examination. This year given to Bachelor of Arts Examination at the 58th Annual Convocation Ceremony.

Smt. Radhabai Narayan Gokhale Prize (02/2009)

for securing the highest number of marks in D.C Music at the Bachelor of Arts Examination at the 58th Annual Convocation Ceremony.

COMPETITIONS

Hindustani Classical Vocal Competition (09/2011)

 Participated and secured Second rank in Khayal gayan competition organised by Sadguru Shri Mamasaheb Deshpande Library, Anandnagar, Pune

Madhukauns (01/2011)

 Participated and emerged as the first prize winner in the Khayal Gayan competition. Demonstrated musical excellence and proficiency in the competition organized by Madhukauns & Gandharva Mahavidyalaya, Pune

Sangeetbhushan Late. Pandit Ram Marathe Smriti Music Competition (10/2010)

- Successfully participated and secured the first prize in the Natyasangeet category.
- Excelled in the Light Music category, winning the first prize.

Rexona Saam Gurukul (2010)

Participated in the reality show aired on Saam TV channel.
 Won the first round, showcasing musical talent and proficiency. Recognized with the 'A Rexona Performer of the Week' award for outstanding performance.

National Youth Festival (04/2010)

 Participated and secured the First Rank in the Indian Group Song category. Represented SNDT University at the National level. Won a Gold Medal, marking the first-time achievement for the university in the music category.

West Zone Youth Festival (12/2009)

- Participated in Semi Classical (Vocal) category and secured Third rank.
- Participated in Indian Group song category and secured second rank.
- Participated in Western Group song category and secured Third rank.

Indradhanushya (11/2009)

- Seventh Maharashtra State Inter- University Youth Festival
- Participated in Western Group song category and secured First rank.
- Participated in Semi Classical (Vocal) category and secured Third rank
- Participated in Indian Group song category and secured Second rank.
- Participated in Folk dance category as a vocal accompanist and secured Second rank.

Swarmadhuri (01/2009)

 Participated and secured the Second Prize in the Indian Classical Singing competition during the Swarmadhuri event.Recognized for musical excellence in the Late Shankarrao Kanitkar Smriti Karandak Music Competition.

West Zone Youth Festival (11/2008)

- Participated in Indian Group song category and secured Third rank
- Participated in Western Group song category and secured Third rank.

Indradhanushya (11/2008)

- Sixth Maharashtra State Inter- University Youth Festival.
- Participated in Indian Group song category and secured First rank
- Participated in Western Group song category and secured Second rank.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Concert Performances

Full-fledged classical concerts, Semi-classical concerts, Light music programs

Project Involvement

Theme songs, jingles, short films Private albums: "Swaramadhuri," "Ragabhawanjali," etc.

Theme-Based Programs

Aayo Phagun Maas, Ghan Barasat Barasat Aale Yaman-raang Chandane Shipit Ja, Sham - E - Ghazal

Collaborations

Vocal accompaniment for Manisha Nrutyalaya (Pta. Manisha tai Sathe) in stage shows, dance performances, and examinations Vocal accompaniment for Nrityavedh (Dr. Madhuri Apte) in stage shows, e.g., "Anuvidha," and other dance performances and examinations

Judging Experience

Jury member, Plexus 2019, M. I. M. E. R. Medical College, Talegaon Dabhade

LANGUAGES

Marathi

English

Hindi

Japanese

INTERESTS



[†] Teaching



Listening Music



Reading books



Swimming



Solving Puzzles



Cooking



Socializing with family & friends



Sudoku

REFERENCES

Dr. Madhuri Dongre

Contact: 9372679677

Dr. Douglas John
Contact: 9821233805

PERFORMANCES

Online lecture demonstration (11/2021)

Organized by Surwardhini Sangeet VIdyalaya, Satara

 Delivered a comprehensive lecture on Raga Sadhana as part of the esteemed "Sangeet - Shodh Astitvacha" series organized by Surwardhini Sangeet Vidyalaya, Satara. Contributed to the intellectual discourse on music, providing valuable insights into the intricacies of Raga Sadhana.

Gazal evening (18/02/2020)

Nine Fish Art Gallery, Byculla, Mumbai

 Successfully coordinated the concluding segment of the art exhibition, featuring the works of renowned artist Shri.
 Manohar Mhatre Ji. Presented a Gazal concert, adding a cultural dimension to the culmination of "An Untitled Legacy."

Kathak Nritya Bhavanjali (24/01/2020)

Annabhau Sathe Auditorium, Satara road, Pune

 Performed as a vocalist providing accompaniment for a Kathak dance performance. Collaborated seamlessly with the Kathak performer to enhance the overall artistic presentation.

Lecture Demonstration (27/11/2019)

Sir. J. J. School of Arts. Mumbai

 Invited to conduct a lecture demonstration on the nuances of Indian Classical Music.Shared insights into the rich heritage and technical aspects of Indian classical musical traditions.

Sham-E-Gazal (6/7/2019)

Nine Fish Art Gallery, Byculla, Mumbai

Pt. Deenanth Smiriti Puraskar (24/04/2019)

Shanmukhananda Auditorium, Sion, Mumbai

Performed as the lead singer in a choir ensemble.
 Demonstrated vocal leadership and musical proficiency in group performances.

Cultural Programme (31/12/2018)

MIT Art Design and Technology University, Loni Kalbhor, Pune

 Performed collaboratively with Kathak dance, enhancing the artistic presentation. Showcased versatility and synergy in musical accompaniment for Kathak performances.

Vijaysandhya (17/10/2018)

MIT World Peace University, Kothrud Campus, Pune

 Participated in a specially designed light music concert to celebrate the birthday of Dr. Vijay Bhatkar.Contributed to the musical program, adding a festive and celebratory atmosphere to the event.

Solo Concert (11/08/2018)

MIT Art Design and Technology University, Loni Kalbhor, Pune

 Received the opportunity to perform in front of all faculty members and students during the University Foundation Day celebration. Contributed to the event by delivering a memorable performance, enhancing the festive spirit of the occasion.

Solo Performance (23/08/2015)

Auditorium, Deenanth Mangeshkar Hospital, Pune

 Presented a performance at the prestigious IV National Conference on Music Therapy organized by Sur Sanjeevan Music Therapy Trust, Mumbai.Contributed to the conference by showcasing musical expertise and understanding of the therapeutic aspects of music.

Sangeet Aswadan Shibir (08/2014)

Manohar Wadhikar Sabhagruha, Dnyanprabodhini Vidyalaya, Nigdi, Pune.

 Facilitated a workshop jointly organized by Mukti Sopan Sangeet Vidyalaya and Pt. Bhimsen Joshi Adhyasan, Pune University. Shared expertise and insights on music.